<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indie on Petr Bouchal</title>
    <link>https://petrbouchal.xyz/cz/tags/indie/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indie on Petr Bouchal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 23:17:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://petrbouchal.xyz/cz/tags/indie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lehká četba na víkend aneb o papírování</title>
      <link>https://petrbouchal.xyz/cz/byrokrates/lehka-cetba-na-vikend-aneb-o-papirovani/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 23:17:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://petrbouchal.xyz/cz/byrokrates/lehka-cetba-na-vikend-aneb-o-papirovani/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;V Byrokratově schránce se sešlo několik odkazů k tématu papírování a byrokracie v tom mondénním smyslu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/bureaucratics1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.janbanning.com/gallery/bureaucratics/&#34;&gt;Bureaucratics&lt;/a&gt;, knížka fotografa Jana Banninga, via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brainpickings.org/index.php/2011/04/04/jan-banning-bureaucratics/?utm_content=bufferf3cdb&amp;amp;utm_source=buffer&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Buffer&amp;amp;buffer_share=b5b8c&#34;&gt;Brainpickings&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; h/t Jan Straka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Bureaucratics [...] is a comparative photographic study of the culture, rituals and symbols of state civil administrations and its servants in eight countries on five continents, selected on the basis of political, historical and cultural considerations.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jan Banning&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/12/17/books/noting-the-history-of-the-paper-trail.html?pagewanted=all&amp;amp;_r=0&#34;&gt;The Paper Trail Through History &lt;/a&gt;(New York Times) je mj. recenzí knihy _The Demon of Writing: The Powers and Failures of Paperwork, _kterou napsal - nevymýšlím si - Ben Kafka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;True, there are not yet any dedicated journals or conferences. But in history, anthropology, literature and media studies departments and beyond, a group of loosely connected scholars are taking a fresh look at office memos, government documents and corporate records, not just for what they say but also for how they circulate and the sometimes unpredictable things they do.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Na to konto jedna klasická bizarní reklama z dílny IBM:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[youtube=http://youtu.be/_IZw2CoYztk]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A na závěr (trochu) vážně: Torben Beck Jørgensen v článku &lt;a href=&#34;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1111/j.1467-9299.2011.01957.x/asset/j.1467-9299.2011.01957.x.pdf?v=1&amp;amp;t=hgjwjedq&amp;amp;s=495ac3302656fe45f8c993da644d1ed1b5cc83b9&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Weber and Kafka: The Rational and the Enigmatic Bureaucracy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, uveřejněném ve váženém odborném časopise _Public Administration _čte Kafkův Zámek pohledem Weberova ideálního typu byrokracie a srovnává tak pohledy těchto dvou současníků na byrokracii. Z abstraktu:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Max Weber’s and Franz Kafka’s respective understandings of bureaucracy are as different as night and day. Yet, Kafka’s novel The Castle is best read with Max Weber at hand. In fact, Kafka
relates systematically to all the dimensions in Weber’s ideal type of bureaucracy and give us a much-contemplated parody, almost a counter-punctual ideal type.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sobotní dodatek:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/17/india-vvip-lights-lal-batti-traffic&#34;&gt;Tenhle článek&lt;/a&gt; o majáčcích na úřednických autech v Díllí sem myslím taky zapadá, zvlášť v kontextu &lt;a href=&#34;http://images.janbanning.com/album/bureaucratics#3&#34;&gt;některých indických fotek&lt;/a&gt; v galerii Jana Banninga.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
